黑客们好，欢迎来到PWN学院
hello hackers welcome to pwn college
这是一个新模块的开始
this is the start of a new module
具体会讲述一些漏洞利用的场景
specifically a module on exploitation scenarios what I mean by that
会融合你在前5个模块所学
is putting together the building blocks that you have Learned so far in the previous 5 modules
构建针对复杂目标的端到端攻击场景
into kind of end to end attacks against more complex targets  than you've seen thus far
或者至少是一个复杂的组合漏洞场景
or  at least more complex combinations of vulnerabilities than you've seen thus far
怎么做呢?好吧
how to do that?  well
让我们先回忆一下我们在课程开始时学的
let's start by remembering what we Learned in the very beginning of the course
在介绍模块中介绍过的菲尼亚斯·费雪
and the introduction module about Phineas Fisher
菲尼亚斯·费雪是个黑客
so Phineas Fisher was a hacker
菲尼亚斯·费雪以图中的玩偶做为自己的形象
represented by this muppet who Phineas Fisher appeared as
接受vice杂志的采访
on an interview with I think vice magazine
在此之前他们由于战胜了黑客团队出名
after their very famous hack against hacking team
菲尼亚斯·费希尔击败黑客团队
and Phineas Fisher compromised hacking team
使用了这些细致的步骤
in this meticulous step by step method
首先他们进行了外部探索
1st they got they performed external reconnaissance
来了解他们面对的是什么
to understand what they're up against
然后他们在网络中获得立足点
they gain the foothold into the network
使用了嵌入式设备上的一个漏洞
using kind of an entry vulnerability on an embedded device
然后他们对内网进行探索
they perform internal reconnaissance on the network
他们逐渐在网络上获得影响力
and they step by step gain influence on the network
持续不断地进行更多的探索
continually performing additional reconnaissance every step of the way
直到打到完全胜利，然后双手插兜
until achieving total compromise and gloating about it
如果你不记得这个故事
if you don't remember this story
可以看一下介绍模块
take a look at the intro module I related there
这是一个非常有趣的端到端真实漏洞攻击的例子
a very interesting example of an end to end real vulnerability compromise
那么我们如何吸取这些教训
so how can we take these lessons
并应用到这门课中呢？好吧
and apply it to this course. well
我们要像菲尼亚斯·费雪那样思考
we want to think like Phineas Fisher
我这么说并不是说去从事网络犯罪
and by this I don't mean go into a life of cyber crime
我在介绍模块中讨论了网络安全伦理
I discussed the ethics of cyber security in the intro module
回去复习一下
go back and review those
但菲尼亚斯·费雪和他们的例子确实介绍了
but Phineas Fisher and their example really introduces
一个非常有趣的框架
a very interesting framework
可以用来处理这些更复杂的场景
with which to approach these more complex expectation scenarios
我们来看看菲尼亚斯·费雪是怎么做的
so let's look through the steps that Phineas Fisher took
致使黑客团队被攻克
to compromise hacking team and
看看这些步骤如何应用到
see how those steps might apply
你们在这个模块中会遇到的各种类型的问题
to the types of problems that you will be facing in this module
步骤大致相同
the steps are roughly the same
首先你拿到一个挑战题
1st you're given a challenge problem
先执行外部探索
perform external reconnaissance
然后用逆向工具,binary ninja、gidra之类的打开它
open it up in a reverse engineering tool and binary ninja gidra what have you
理解它是如何工作的
understand how it works
运行它
run it
与之互动
interact with it
考虑哪些功能可能是脆弱的
consider what functionality might be vulnerable
当然，脆弱的功能是
and of course the functionality that's going to be vulnerable
肯定是你可以直接交互的
is going to be the functionality that you can interact with directly
和你的输入有接触的
that your user input touches
它会处理你的用户输入等等
that processes your user input and so forth
一旦你找到了潜在的易受攻击的功能
then once you have an idea of potential vulnerable functionality
你要想利用它
you want to exploit it
先要找到最小的安全漏洞
find the smallest security hole
也许在输入处理过程有一个off by one问题
maybe there is an off by one error in a input processing routine
也许是栈缓冲区溢出
maybe there's a stack buffer overflow
也许在长度检查中存在有无符号问题
maybe there is a signedness error in a length check
找到最小的安全漏洞并加以利用
find that smallest security hole and exploit it
比如，溢出缓冲区，然后
overflow the buffer for example and then
进行内部调查
do the internal reconnaissance
停下来看看我的这一步取得了什么成就
stop and look at what did my single step achieve
我溢出了缓冲区
right I overflowed the buffer
我获得了什么额外的控制权
what have I achieved additional control over
下一步我还能做什么
what else can I do as the next step
我现在在程序中找到哪些其他漏洞
what other vulnerabilities have I now introduced into the program
可以让我
that might allow me to take
继续获得对程序状态的额外影响
continue to gain additional influence over the program state
当然，第四步是获得影响力
and then of course step 4 is gaining that influence
步骤4是继续使用
step 4 is continuing to use
你在程序中找到的其他缺点
the additional weaknesses that you have now introduced into the program
利用在漏洞上获得
by taking advantage of one vulnerability
的能力不断的构建组合
to continually chain and build on the capabilities
你，作为一个攻击者，在程序中拥有的能力
that you as  an attacker have within the program
当然光说是相当模糊的
of course this is fairly vague
而且情况会根据要攻击的程序不同而不同
uh very much depends on the programs you're trying to exploit
这个模块就是通过实践来学习
and this module will really be about learning through practice
但总的步骤是这样的
but the general steps are these right
第5步，在经过内部探索
of course step 5 after going through the internal reconnaissance
了解了你对程序有哪些控制
understanding what control you have over the program
了解了下一步你可以采取的措施
understanding what potential next steps you can take
最终，该程序将被彻底占领
eventually the program will be completely compromised
你攻击的计算机系统将会完全沦陷
the computer system that you're attacking will be completely broken
然后你可以继续到第6步
and then you can move on to step 6
读取flag并提交
read out the flag and submit it
这是一门艺术
this is very much an art
对吧
right
你创造一个漏洞利用
you are creating an exploit
你是在凭空创造功能
you're creating functionality out of thin air
创造起初程序中不存在的功能
functionality that did not exist in that program when you started
你们将在这些模块中看到的程序
the programs that you will be seeing in these modules
从未被设计为读取flag文件
were never designed to read the flag file
从来没有被设计用来执行任意代码
were never designed to execute arbitrary code
他们只是想做一件非常小的事情
they were very much meant to do a very small thing
读入你的名字，说你好
read in your name and say hello
或在限制了打开文件功能的计算机里执行代码
or execute code in an esoteric computer architecture for which the opening of files has been disabled
诸如此类的事情
these sort of things and
你要让这些程序
you will have to take those programs
跟着你的指挥翩翩起舞
and you'll have to force them to dance to your own music
要做到这样。你要用到目前为止在这门课上学到的东西
you'll do that by putting together everything you've Learned in the course thus far
并将其组合应用以实现完全控制
and applying it in tandem to achieve complete control
本模块接下来的视频
the rest of the videos in this module
我将通过几个非常具体的例子来说明这种情况
I'll go through a couple of very specific examples of these sort of situations
在练习题目中还有更多
and in the practice problems there will be significantly more
练习题目里的是这个模块的高价值内容
the practice problems is where the meat of this module will really come across um
这是我们在PWN学院尝试的一项新举措
this is a new thing that we're trying with pwn college
希望一切顺利
hopefully it works out great
并且
and
你能巩固迄今为止所学到的知识
you solidify the knowledge that you've gained thus far
接下来的视频再见
see you in the rest of the videos